Ali Asghari

PhD Student of Engineering The University of Melbourne Phone: +61 452 255 189

E-mail: aasghari@student.unimelb.edu.au

Introduction

Ali is a PhD candidate at the Infrastructure department at the University of Melbourne, Australia. Working within divers industrial and academic environments, he has gained a wealth of technical and analytical expertise as well as teaching and academic skills. Having gained some experiences in surveying, spatial data science, machine learning and teaching in Geomatics as a multidisciplinary area, he has capitalised to a great extent in data science, Geographic Information System (GIS) and geospatial analysis, Remote Sensing (RS) and Land Administration Systems (LAS) as well as university teaching and assisting students to progress in their studies. To expand his knowledge around 3D geospatial data science, he perused a PhD in the Centre for Spatial Data Infrastructures and Land Administration (CSDILA) focusing on developing algorithms and methods for 3D spatial data validation. His research is one of the work package of an ARC linkage project namely "3D Property Ownership Map Base for Smart Urban Land Administration" which is a collaborative project between CSDILA and Land Use Victoria, Intergovernmental Committee on Surveying and Mapping (ICSM) and City of Melbourne. This has consolidated his understanding of a range of 3D modelling techniques, 3D geospatial data science, Java and C++ programming, software development and 3D spatial data validation and analysis.

Education

2004

2018 - Present	Doctor of Philosophy – Engineering, Infrastructure Engineering
	Department, School of Engineering, The University of Melbourne,
	Parkville, Victoria, Australia
2013-2016	Master's Degree: Remote Sensing & Geographic Information System,
	Remote Sensing and GIS Department, Shahid Beheshti University,
	Tehran, Iran
	GPA: 19.41 out of 20
2005-2009	Bachelor's Degree: Geomatics Engineering, Iran University of Science
	and Technology, Arak, Iran
	GPA: 16.18 out of 20

Diploma: Mathematics and Physics, Tehran, Iran

GPA: 19.23 out of 20

Honour and Awards

Melbourne Research Scholarship to undertake the Doctor of Philosophy – Engineering at The University of Melbourne, Australia (2018).

The Rowden White Scholarship to undertake the Doctor of Philosophy – Engineering at The University of Melbourne, Australia (2018).

Melbourne School of Engineering Studentship to undertake the Doctor of Philosophy – Engineering at The University of Melbourne, Australia (2018)

Melbourne Studentship to undertake the Doctor of Philosophy – Engineering at The University of Melbourne, Australia (2019)

Iranian Science and Research Scholarship for B.E (Tuition waiver; 2005-2009) **Rank 6329** in the Nationwide Bachelor's Program Admission Examination among 367,627 participants in Iran (2004).

Graduation Certificate for participation in the SSSI National Young Professionals Mentoring Program 2019 as a mentee.

1st Ranked Student during all Elementary, Intermediate and High school periods.

5th Ranked Student in bachelor's among 52 students.

2nd Ranked Student in master's among 12 students.

Publications

Asghari, A., Kalantari, M. and Rajabifard, A., 2019. A structured framework for 3D cadastral data validation—a case study for Victoria, Australia. Land Use Policy, p.104359; https://doi.org/10.1016/j.landusepol.2019.104359

Shafizadeh-Moghadam, H., **Asghari, A.**, Taleai, M., Helbich, M. and Tayyebi, A., 2017. Sensitivity analysis and accuracy assessment of the land transformation model using cellular automata. GIScience & Remote Sensing, 54(5), pp.639-656. https://doi.org/10.1080/15481603.2017.1309125

Shafizadeh-Moghadam, H., **Asghari, A.**, Taleai, M., Helbich, M. and Tayyebi, A., 2017. Sensitivity analysis and accuracy assessment of the land transformation model using cellular automata. GIScience & Remote Sensing, 54(5), pp.639-656. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compenvurbsys.2017.04.002

Submitted manuscripts (under review):

Asghari, A., Kalantari, M. and Rajabifard, A., 2020. Advancement in techniques to formulate 3D misclosure for cadastre. Transaction in GIS.

Shafizadeh-Moghadam, H., Minaei, M., Pontius, RG., Asghari, A., Dadashpour, H., 2020.

Feature selection based Random Forest to simulate urban growth and ranking ephemeral urban drive. International Journal of Geographical Information Science.

Conference papers and presentations:

Feb 2020 - ARC linkage 3D project seminar, 3D Cadastral Data Validation.

Nov 2019 - Infrastructure Engineering Post Graduate Conference, The University of Melbourne, Australia. 3D Cadastral Data Validation,

https://infrastructure.eng.unimelb.edu.au/people/abstracts/Ali-Asghari-2019.pdf

Professional Service (Manuscript Reviewer)

Transaction in GIS journal (2 journal articles)
Journal of Spatial Science (2 journal articles)

Teaching Experiences

The University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia:

May 2020 | Lecturer

• Subject: *Engineering Site Characterisation*| Topic: Introduction to Surveying, Levelling, GIS and GPS

Nov 2019 | Tutor/Instructor

 Workshop: BIM & Modern Urban Land Administration Training Program Topic: Data Quality

Oct 2019 | Guest lecturer

• Subject: Land administration | Topic: 3D cadastral data validation

Jul 2019 - Nov 2019 | Tutor/Instructor

• Subject: Spatial Analysis

April 2019 – May 2019 | Lecturer

 Subject: Engineering Site Characterisation | Topic: Introduction to Surveying, Levelling, GIS and GPS

Aug 2018 | Tutor/Instructor

• Subject: Spatial Analysis | Topic: Field analysis and interpolation techniques

Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran:

December 2014 | Tutor/Instructor

• Workshop: Interpretation of Satellite Images in Water and Soil Resources

May 2014 | Tutor/Instructor

• Workshop: Hydrology of Surface Water with an Emphasis on Iran

K. N. Toosi University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

2017 | Tutor/Instructor

• Subject: Geographic information system

Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran:

Nov 2016 - Jan 2017 | Tutor/Instructor

• Subject: Geographic information system in environmental science

Work experiences and collaboration with research projects

	r -3
Jan 2020 – Present	The "Fishermans Bend Digital Twin" project
Postgraduate researcher	Sharing ideas and outcomes regarding 3D data validation to be
	implemented on digital twin platform
Nov 2019 – Present	ESD 2 Development Work - flooding project
3D geospatial data analyst	Converting 3D model data (OBJ) into 3D printable files, The
	University of Melbourne, Australia
Apr 2018 – May 2018	Malaysian 3D Cadastre project
Postgraduate researcher	Develop and implement a prototype 3D cadastral system for
	Malaysia.
Feb 2018 – Present	ARC linkage project "3D Property Ownership Map Base for
Postgraduate researcher	Smart Urban Land Administration"
_	Validating single 3D property objects and the connectivity
	relationship of each 3D property object
Sep 2014 – Sep 2017	Surveying and mapping of infrastructure developments
Surveying Engineer	Petro Poulad Pars Company, Tehran, Iran

May 2013-Sep 20144 Residential SkyScrapers ProjectHead of SurveyingHavaFaza Company, Tehran, Iran

April 2012-Sep 2013 Construction Project

Surveying Engineer TakSamanHoor Company, Tehran, Iran

Sep 2009- Oct 2010 Tehran Metro Line 4 (Underground developments for metro)
Surveying Engineer International Energy and Management Processing Company,

Tehran, Iran

Skills and Expertise

• Java, JOGL and C++ programing with a tendency towards the computational geometry algorithms

- Professional work experience with 3D geospatial data software including Autodesk Revit, Solibri Model Viewer, Autodesk Netfabb Premium, TinkerCad and Meshmixer
- Professional work experience with geospatial data software including ArcGIS, QGIS, ENVI and ERDAS Imagine.
- R programming (With tendency in spatial statistics and machine learning)
- MATLAB programming
- Python programming (With a a good experience using ArcPy site-package in ArcGIS software)
- Spatial databases management PostgreSQL and SQL server
- Work experience with data mining software including KEEL and WEKA
- Professional work experience with civil and surveying software including AutoCAD,
 Surfer and Civil3D Land Desktop

References

Associate Professor Mohsen kalantari,

Department of Infrastructure Engineering, School of Engineering, The University of

Melbourne, VIC 3010, Australia

Phone: +61 3 8344 0274

Email: mohsen.kalantari@unimelb.edu.au

Professor Abbas Rajabifard,

Head, Department of Infrastructure Engineering, School of Engineering, The University of

Melbourne, VIC 3010, Australia

Mobile: +61 3 8344 0234

Email: abbas.r@unimelb.edu.au